A Guide to the Heslip M. "Happy" Lee Papers, 1915-2003
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
- Two metal medallions, n.d., "Adolph Hitler" with a cutout of a Nazi swastika and "Member KKK in Good Standing." (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Plastic bag of cotton plant balls, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Two signs collected by Lee, 1915 and n.d., "No dogs, negroes, Mexicans" by Lonestar Restaurant Association and "Colored Waiting Room" by Boston Sign Company. (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Jimmy Carter Personal Peanut Power Souvenir Campaign Material Kit, ca. 1976 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Certificates and plaques, 1964-2001 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  Contains certificate, 29 October 1964, issue to Happy Lee by the Virginia Teachers Association; certificate, 29 November 1964, issued to Happy Lee by the First Unitarian Church (Richmond, Virginia); certificate, 6 April 1969, issued to Happy Lee by WKIX radio; certificate, 12 January 1971, appointing Happy Lee as Lieutenant Colonel, Aide de Camp, of the Governor's Staff; certificate, 22 September 1973, issued to Happy Lee by the College of Philanthropy of the Virginia Council on Human Relations; certificate, 1976-1977, issued to community leaders on behalf of the Bicentenial Memorial; certificate, 1979-1980, issued to Happy Lee by the Red Cross; plaque, 2001, issued to Happy Lee by the State of Georgia for outstanding citizenry; certificate, n.d., issued to Happy Lee by the National University Extension Association; and plaque, n.d., presented to Happy Lee by the Historical Preservations of America.
- Published drawings of Walter Rauschenbusch and Francis of Assisi, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Look Magazine, 12 November 1968 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Past Times, August 1995 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Life magazine, 14 June 1968, 22 November 1968, 6 December 1968, and 20 December 1968 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Audio cassettes, 6 February 1986, 10 and 24 April 1988, Happy Lee sermons and Coretta Scott King speech to the SLC in Utah. (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Video tapes, 1997, "Happy Lee Nuggets," and "Happy Lee: Various Stories" are in this folder. (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Two rolls of nickels, 1995, Given to Lee by a member of the Glen Falls Baptist Church. (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous newspaper clippings, 1926, 1963-1986, Concerns King assassination, Nixon resignation, John F. Kennedy assassination, Jimmy Carter presidential win, and Apollo moon landing. (Boxes 15-16)
- Miscellaneous newspaper clippings, 1949-1960, Concerns Mercer University (Macon, Georgia) students and student activities, Lee employment at Mercer, Lee's church activities in Polk County, Georgia, Lee's activities as a preacher in Georgia, Lee at Colgate College and Rochester Divinity School, and includes images of Happy Lee in newspapers. There is also information concerning Polk County, Georgia, history, the Brown vs. Board of Education decision, and other race and segregation matters. Notable churches mentioned are the Antioch Baptist Church, Hancock Church, and York Baptist Church in New York. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  Chronologically with undated clippings at the beginning of the folder.
- Miscellaneous newspaper clippings, 1961-1964, Principally concerns Virginia Human Relations Council, Lee speaking engagements, Lee honors from community and religious groups, Lee statements against racism and segregation, the arrest of 16 students in civil rights case, the United States Civil Rights Bill, and the Danville Civil Rights Demonstrations. (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous newspaper clippings, 1965-1969, Principally concerns Happy Lee's appointment at North Carolina State University, public schools, integration and race relations in North Carolina, Lee's employment in and around Atlanta, Georgia, anti-poverty drives sponsored and led by Lee, VISTA crews in Rowan, and Lee's service as executive director of the Salisbury-Rowan Community Service Center. (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous newspaper clippings, 1970-1975, Principally concerns Lee's community service activities in and near Atlanta, Georgia, and Georgia State University, and public schools and race relations in Hickory, North Carolina. There are also various clippings containing an image of Happy Lee. (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous newspaper clippings, 1976-2003, Concerns Lee with Georgia state politicians, Lee family matters and family members, Lee public service in Cedartown, Georgia, Lee political activity, Lee's activities as interim pastor of First Baptist Church, Glen Falls, New York, Lee ministry in Manhattan, New York, Lee speaking engagements, Lee awards and recognition by community and religious groups, and Lee service as Seventh District Chairman. Also includes clippings of Lee's letters to the editor and articles printed in the paper. (Box 16, Folder 5)